Hugo Fernando Zapata.

Software Developer.

Email	hugozap@gmail.com
GitHub	http://github.com/hugozap
Telephone (U.S Number)	(312) 212-3753
WebSite / Blog	http://www.hugozap.com.
Current country of residence (Available for relocation / remote work.)	Colombia

Hi My name is Hugo Zapata, I've been working in software projects for about 9 years, from server side projects to mobile. Currently I enjoy FrontEnd engineering and Web technologies in general, however I'm good learning new skills and technology stacks if required. I try to be involved with local tech communities and have presented topics i'm interested in.

Related skills:

- Define the architecture for Web applications in the FrontEnd, and create specifications / guides for the team (or myself)
- Develop applications / modules with JavaScript (FrontEnd and server side with Node).
- Instruct other developers and guide them in the use of good practices to keep the projects healthy.
- Learning new technology stacks when required.
- Graphics programming (computer graphics, visualizations, SVG)
- Creating scripts to automate development tasks / workflow.
- General problem solving.
- Train junior developers.

Some Technology stacks I have experience with:

- NodeJS for server side apps and integration utilities.
- NodeJS Streams.
- Web apps with Browserify.
- Web technologies and utilities. (Html/Js/ knockout.js / LESS, template libs...)
- Mobile applications for Android using Java.
- CoronaSDK apps using LUA programming language.
- UNIX Operative systems.
- Microsoft .NET stack (C# , ASP MVC)

Education.

Systems Engineering, Javeriana University (Bogotá Colombia) 2007

Talks:

Talks i've given to the local tech communities:

- NodeJS Streams (2014, BogotaJS)
- High level tests with CasperJS (2013, BogotaJS)
- Jquery Mobile (Microsoft Innovation Day 2011)
- JQuery Tour (HubBog 2011)

Work Experience.

Sears Holding Corporation.

Aug 2014 – Jun 2015.

City: Bogotá (Colombia) and Chicago (USA)

Worked as FrontEnd Engineer developing custom widgets for Sears websites. My role included creating specifications, prototypes and working the backend team to coordinate Api integration. I worked remotely most of the time but also traveled to Chicago for some months when it was required.

Technical director Obassi ltd.

(City: Bogotá)

Nov 2011 - Aug 2014

Obassi is the brand I usually use when I work as contractor for other companies. I worked with multiple clients creating Web and mobile products like www.visualsale.com, a Web/mobile platform built in Java(Android) and ASP MVC for backend.

Freelancing

2009 - 2011

Worked as a freelance software developer for multiple clients, mostly in Bogotá Colombia.

Software Developer at Vision Software

(City: Santiago – Chile)

Apr – Nov 2008

Worked on data integration using the .NET stack and the BPM product Bizagi. The location of the work was Santiago (Chile) and the client was TATA.

Software Developer at TES America Andina

City: Bogotá
Jan – Jun 2007

I worked doing Windows Client development using the MS .NET stack with C#. The particular project

I worked in was a Windows Application for a Cellphone carrier company used to manage the deployment of Cellular networks.